Ronnie Rogers

Ontario, California

RonnieXRogers@icloud.com | (909) 450-1244

Github Portfolio | Linked In

Refrigeration technician turned software developer with a passion for technology. I create new functionality as well as specialize in debugging and maintaining current applications. I'm driven by my team's success as well as creating new and exciting products. I offer a unique skill set of diagnostic abilities as well as a huge passion for learning and teaching others so that we can all flourish.

Skills

- Frontend programming in Javascript, React.JS, and HTML5
- Frontend styling utilizing Reactstrap, Bootstrap, and CSS
- Backend programming utilizing Node.JS, Express, and MongoDB
- Ability to create, maintain, and debug web applications

Experience

December 2021 - Present

General Assembly - Software Engineering Immersive Fellow - *Remote*

- Create functional full stack web applications in Javascript and Python
- Create and maintained my own APIs using MongoDB and Mongoose
- Utilize Javascript and React JS to build frontend web applications with API calls
- Style front end applications utilizing Bootstrap, Reactstrap, and CSS
- Created a full stack web application for a salon. The site utilized React.JS, Node.JS, Express, MongoDB, and AWS S3. Allows users to sign in and create appointments with photo upload. Allows the admin to login, view/edit appointments, and upload/edit their photo gallery.
- Created a recipe finder React.js application that pulls data from an API using user input to generate a list of recipes based on that criteria
- Created a full stack personal calendar MERN application that allows users create an account, input events to their personal planner, and view the events on their calendar
- Created a Blackjack game using Javascript, CSS, and HTML5 in which a user can play against A.I. The game features a live score keeper as well as sound effects and music.

June 2021 - January 2022

Albertsons - Refrigeration Technician - *Fullerton, CA*

- Programmed, repaired, and maintained Building Management Systems
- Troubleshot and repaired high voltage electrical circuits and low voltage circuits
- Utilized BMS control systems to control and monitor store refrigeration and lighting
- Maintained and monitored multiple stores to ensure 0 product loss and no downtime

Diagnosed, repaired, and maintained all aspects of supermarket refrigeration including:
 Parallel rack systems, self-contained units, frozen food cases, medium temp cases, and walk-in boxes

February 2019 - June 2021

Ralphs Grocery Company - Refrigeration Technician - Compton, CA

- Programmed, repaired, and maintained Building Management Systems
- Troubleshot and repaired high voltage electrical circuits and low voltage circuits
- Utilized the proprietary F.A.S.T. application to remotely monitor store refrigeration and trigger alarms if issues were present
- Utilized BMS control systems to control lighting
- Maintained and monitored multiple stores to ensure no downtime and 0 product loss
- Diagnosed, repaired, and maintained all aspects of supermarket refrigeration including:
 Parallel rack systems, self-contained units, frozen food cases, medium temp cases, and walk-in boxes

May 2016 - February 2019

C&L Refrigeration - HVAC Technician - *Fullerton, CA*

- Repaired, programmed, and maintained Building Management Systems
- Troubleshot and repaired high voltage electrical circuits and low voltage circuits
- Utilized BMS to control and monitor building HVAC and lighting
- Diagnosed, repaired, and maintained all aspects of building HVAC including: rooftop package units, split-systems, chillers, boilers, ductless-splits, and ventilation systems.

Education

December 2021 - March 2022

General Assembly - Software Engineering Immersive - *Remote*